Alejandro Núñez Pérez

 • Granada, Spain
 • ■ alejnp@proton.me
 • Inlinkedin.com/in/alejnp
 • • github.com/alxe

About Me _____

Hello! I'm Alejandro, a Software Engineer with over five years of experience across multiple roles. These include technical Support with a focus on personal interaction and management, and actual Development for both traditionally and as-a-Service deployed software, using different stacks.

When it comes to work, I am most interested in building information transformation pipelines. But overall, I am happy with taking on new challenges and sharing my own knowledge with my peers.

Education _____

MBA Ediae, Cámara de Comercio, Business - Granada, Spain

Nov 2024 – present

General MBA focused on wide-area knowledge of managing a business, including Strategy, Marketing and Finances.

- **BS** Universidad de Granada, Computer Science Granada, Spain Sept 2015 Sept 2019 Basics of Computer Science, including Algorithm Design, Data Structures, Networking and Distributed Systems.
 - · Honors in Modern Multi-paradigm Programming.

Experience _____

Senior Software Engineer, Real-Time Innovations – Hybrid (Granada or Remote) Apr 2024 – present Part of the API, later GPP development teams focused on the Connext Professional products.

- Maintained an internal, distributed testing Python framework for RTI products.
- Retrofitted the Java API while keeping backwards compatibility, reduced the number of known memory leaks by >90%.
- Developed a new internal web server for storing performance data using FastAPI, with a MongoDB database backend.

Software Engineer, Real-Time Innovations – Hybrid (Granada or Remote)

Nov 2019 – Apr 2024

Part of the Support team, providing low-level, technical support to worldwide customers across multiple industry verticals, with a focus on the EMEA and APAC regions.

- Resolved customer time-sensitive escalations on critical deployments.
- · Maintained multiple branches of support releases, built and delivered patches.
- · Led newcomers through onboarding, taught soft and hard skills.

Hard Skills

JVM: Very well-versed in Java, have dabbled with Kotlin, Scala and Groovy. Familiar with JVM internals and JNI

Python: Very well-versed in Python and popular frameworks. Built and internally distributed multiple packages

JavaScript: Acquainted with the language and Node-specific FFI packages such as Koffi

Soft Skills _____

Communication: Well versed in written and spoken communication, internal or external

People Management: Acquainted in mentoring and managing people